<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-05T13:31:39+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">thewordsmithsoul</title><subtitle>From, Vamika Arora ❤️ Composed of vanilla matcha and psychology. Surveying the wreck of the world with an air of concern and dredging the mysteries of life with amusement.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">It’s okay to be not okay! 💐</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/30/Its-okay-to-be-not-okay.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It’s okay to be not okay! 💐" /><published>2019-04-30T02:42:54+08:00</published><updated>2019-04-30T02:42:54+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/30/Its-okay-to-be-not-okay</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/30/Its-okay-to-be-not-okay.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m someone who has read a lot about Depression, Phobia or maybe free floating anxiety that one faces. Intertwined with terminology for such feelings, I have felt a few of them in my life, also have encountered various instances in a hospital setting while busy with my internship experience trying to imbibe everything. I saw a dialectial difference between how at the outset of these definitions. The affective component, cognitive component, physiological component and the social component, everything contributed to this grid of people who fall under such feelings. Some while naming these demons that would be swayed away from shamans, some forced to enter the hospital while reaching at the boundary of maladaptiveness and merely few who recognise these feelings as something that need attention from a proper source. 
Such emotions though hard to acceptance in a social as well within the interiority of oneself. It’s a feeling that each one of us keep it as a story under our beds of sub-consciousness, a story which is right under our throat but everytime someone merely narrates such feeling, all we are trying to gulp it down more harder. Everyone has faced it and I studying this subject, have been not at the receiving end of a special treatment of not having to do anything with such feelings. A scary place it is, but one message that returns to me each day is - it is okay to be not okay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all go through some disturbing phase in life, our ups and downs, no matter who you are. We are always going to have troubles in life and for each of us recognising this is a challenge to almost this feeling leaving us in a vulnerable shell. Sometimes this shell could contain us well for a definite amount of time and sometimes the shell needs repairing. But that doesn’t meet that the shell was not strong enough, it is our responsibility to feed our shell and repair it each day. It is not because I’m a student of this discipline, but because I’m just another person in this world feeling what each one of you must have felt sometime. Maybe my tale is a little different, maybe my affect is placed in a different spectrum that yours, but my story just like any one of yours. Would pave way for understanding what emotions are capable of and what humans who face such emotions are no different to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think life is full of obstacles and each one of us are fighting our best. One is basically trying to solve one question and get to another question, over and over. That’s what life is. As we are trying to complicate these questions a little by sometimes not seeking answers by sharing or asking for help- it is becoming more challenging. I know at the bay of vulnerability, one feels a sense of dependence and loss of one’s control. I have felt that. But what if the illusionary control that we all are seeking is nothing but hiding the tales that might not be heroic in nature but a tale that is truthful enough to the other. Maybe we all are in this voyage, discovering life with various emotions. And maybe somebody who took a different route knows the way better than you do. And maybe just maybe, you are better thorough with the route that he/she might be stepping in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not asking for a journey of wisdom here, just a journey of acceptance. Being able to encourage the people near you to get the help they need. Maybe certain emotions could be benefitted by sharing with certain friends and maybe this time changing the topic about what you really feel about life rather than just addressing the whereabouts in a socially accepted way. Infact, what is socially accepted anyway? If that conduct, cannot help us all grow together. I want each one of you, the very next time in your lives when a person sits with you and shares or even seems not okay. Rather than hiding away those gulps remind him/her that it is okay to be not okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s okay to ask for help, whether it’s talking to a therapist or going to psychiatrist, whether it’s talking to your friend or the solace you find in art or nature. It’s important. I want each one you to realise that Mental Health is important and struggle is real. And no matter how better each one of you hide it, maybe the intensity is different but each one is capable of recognising these emotions. There are a lot of people who are hiding away from it, not recognising that suppression is just the start of the tale to it’s more uninhibited forms. For me able to save someone’s life by once recognising that even I have faced certain emotion or maybe leading them towards the right help, is important than a Gold medal. For me maybe, there is no potential that is infinitely greater than helping the other person grow. For me, I cannot settle in telling myself I’m okay and sometimes others too, as I have realised that it is okay to be not okay.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Maybe it’s time to let the old ways die.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/25/Maybe-its-time-to-let-the-old-ways-die.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maybe it's time to let the old ways die." /><published>2019-04-25T02:42:54+08:00</published><updated>2019-04-25T02:42:54+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/25/Maybe-its-time-to-let-the-old-ways-die</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/25/Maybe-its-time-to-let-the-old-ways-die.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among all the array of positive human emotions, one emotion kept under the carpet but each of us, as we face variety of situations are assailed by feelings of grief and also of anger.  These emotions can be very hard to express, for fear of upsetting other people, or making them feel that they somehow have to find a solution to your sadness. Personally, I have always been afraid of anger. I did not realise this until in one of my psychology classes, I identified my reluctance to express or even admit to any kind of angry feelings. There was a lot of anger around several issues. I think what was almost worse than the anger was the threat of it. Something would upset the balance in the family home, and we would then all play a collective waiting game: would the emotions dissipate, or would they erupt into something much more terrible and destructive?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anger always lay at the origin of these explosions of emotion, and much time and thought therefore needed to be dedicated to its avoidance. Most often on the receiving end of my parents’ anger, I failed to recognise my own, and certainly did not express it. Rather, I subconsciously repackaged it as sadness or self-loathing and turned it inwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over my years while exploring the varsity of spectrum of human emotions, I have come 
to understand that anger can be expressed and that in fact it often needs to be. As Dr Harriet Lerner says that anger is a signal that we should listen to. Feelings of anger might mean that we are being hurt, that our rights are being violated, that our needs are not being met adequately, or that we are not addressing an important emotional issue in our lives. From my own point of view, the first step was acknowledging and accepting that anger was an emotion one could actually feel. In discussions with myself over the nights that clinged onto finding a right path to express anger and to explore the healthy outlets, I would often wonder about being upset, stressed, or in a state of panic.
Frequently, I would reflect these emotional experiences back to me as an expression of my anger, which I sometimes heard in my own voice, even if I was in a state of awareness yet unaware of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through these years, it became clear that I had come to see anger as a purely negative emotion and one that was to be avoided, largely due  to the sense of threat I associated with it in my childhood, Over time, I have come to understand, as is the case with many emotions, that anger in and of itself is neither good nor bad. Rather, the consequences of anger depend on how a person responds to their emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anger can be perceived as a negative emotion due to the nature of the external factors that may trigger it, such as bullying, humiliation or loss. Anger can also be caused by internal factors such as frustration or failure.  An outburst of anger may be preceded by negative thought patterns, which can further cement our perception of anger as negative or harmful, and which also illustrate how anger is often less to do with an event and more to do with our personal response to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anger may result from a process of blaming someone else for negative events or emotions. An individual may seek to attribute blame in order to avoid personal responsibility or a sense of shame, and anger displaces those feelings onto another person. Anger may follow a psychological process of generalisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In moments of stress in particular, we can have a tendency to see things in black and white. We use words like ‘always’ or ‘never’ to describe a situation, with the result of making it seem worse than it actually is, and making our emotional reaction to it more extreme. In other situations, we may keep a mental tally of perceived injustices, which build until we add the final straw. We then erupt in anger that may be experienced by others as an overreaction. If we want to engage with our anger but also manage it and make it more proportionate to events, we need to challenge these negative thought processes.This can be easier said than done, not least when our feelings of anger are so powerful that it is difficult to consider them rationally. Holding onto these thoughts, I tried to identify my anger, I felt a loss of emotional control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interactions with people around me - in particular my family, were often governed by the anger that I suddenly realised I felt, whether or not it related to the moment I was in.
While over time my ability to manage my anger has improved, this remains one of the reasons I find anger such a difficult emotion. I still feel that there is a floodgate holding back a whole tidal wave of feeling. Expressing one’s anger is a huge risk, since the anger of the moment may be overtaken by the anger one have held at bay on countless previous occasions. It is often difficult to identify the precise origins of one’s feelings of anger in any one moment, and in that scenario one feels that both I and my interlocutor are at risk from my emotions. The more one is able to acknowledge and reflect on their anger, the more they are able to find safe ways to express it. However, it is still extremely difficult not to turn one’s anger inwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I have encountered a tendency in people to think about how dissatisfied they are with their life. Rationally, I can see that angrily blaming oneself for poor choices one has made is self-destructive; angrily blaming a vague notion of Fate or chance creates a sense of hopelessness, which can also lead to self-destructive impulses. Acknowledging one’s anger as an indication that something needs to change, and seeing it as a positive signal that will hopefully enable one to feel a sense of agency in that process of change – ‘I can do things differently’ - helps one to see anger in a different light. I recognise that as an emotion it can be as helpful a signpost to one as other, more conventionally positive feelings. There is still some way to go before one can be completely open with oneself and others about the anger that one feels. However, for some therapy and for others a practice of self exploration would give them the opportunity to acknowledge and express anger in a safe place. As one becomes more honest with themselves about their anger. One notices that expression of anger could be paved through a smooth pathway which doesn’t have to belittled under passivity but rather an emotion which one recognises.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">That One Day! ❤️️</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/09/That-one-day.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="That One Day! ❤️️" /><published>2019-03-09T02:42:54+08:00</published><updated>2019-03-09T02:42:54+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/09/That-one-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/09/That-one-day.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be that one day, when we will realise that it is not the perfect sonnet, perfect place or the perfect person that we are looking for. But instead! One day you will realise that the person smiling through his little imperfections, that he doesn’t pushes off but rather sits with you to explain them bit by bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day his smile will fill up the small room and you will imagine how that small room, the feel of his arms, the light in the window, the songs that he sends, the afternoons, the evenings, the nights, the bodies that spilled together while sleeping, the tiny flowing currents that you almost resist each time you see that person walking with you on the path that leads to the destination. But oh that beautiful path! You just never want it to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day you will realise that maybe, that person with those strong arms, those little sparkly eyes and that loud laughter is the whole world that you once asked for. And almost forgot as a wish!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day you will find that even corners shared with him is a space that fills up the whole room in the interiors of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day as you are walking, you will listen to the stories narrated by him. And despite all those intricacies of the narration, you will be interested in how excited he is, how his face lights up and how he rushes his arms here and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day your hands would automatically entangle with his and your heart will beat a little fast. But after a second, when he will hold onto them better. You will feel a sense of calm. One day in a room with multiple things, his eyes would be the most beautiful to stare at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, that you realise that you have found him. And it is not exactly the way that you had planned. You will realise that maybe he was the plan. I almost forgot, it’s this day that you should hold on to and tell him that whether it’s his WWE boxing fever or his cricket mania. Whether it’s happiness, sadness or a little fight you orchestrate for boredom. Tell him that this one day, you promise to love him each ‘one day’. Maybe this one day seems distant to some. But when it will be there, I want each one of you to turn this one day to each day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I want you! ✨</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/09/I-want-you.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I want you! ✨" /><published>2019-03-09T02:42:54+08:00</published><updated>2019-03-09T02:42:54+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/09/I-want-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/09/I-want-you.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want your Monday morning sleep soaked eyes dream drenched voice, lazy bones ‘five more minutes please, baby.’ I want your Tuesday afternoon coffee break, glasses off, laughter on, ‘hold me tight, it’s been a hard day.’ I want your Wednesday evening fingers through hair, neck craning, eye glazing and tired voice that utters that ‘this paperwork never ends’, which sounds almost music to me. I want your Thursday night drinks for two bones, unbind muscles, let loose flats, uttering that “ I want just you and me’. I want your Friday finally stretch soul smile, sun slipping light from the glaciers in your eyes, fingers unfurl, where your voice is sleepy but you are way too excited to listen to my stories. I want your wild, I want your calm. All composed under that interiority of love. I want your weekend, your movie marathon saturday, listening to my poetry, following your playlist. But more than any story, I’m hooked at your gaze. I want your Sunday morning orange juice and pancakes, holding onto each other just to murmur that ‘let’s not get out of bed today’. Just as much as I want your good days, I want your bad days too. I want your drunk voice which makes me weak in the knees, I want your lazy and embrace your lonely. I want that fist full fight that ends up in tickling. Who said love was grand gestures? I want you each day in whatever form you wish to take that day. I want to walk in the corridor and those lifts where standing close to you feels that I walk with home. I want that sleepy voice which fades away in sleep. But still remembers to wish goodnight. I want you everyday in every way for the rest of my life. I want to decorate my life with the monotony of your existence. Because I know if it’s you, it is like your existence sings to me each day. And the tunes as much as it excites me and calm it, I’m hooked at it’s enchantment. People want love stories, I just want a routine decorated with love from you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I enjoy loneliness.🍁</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/05/I-enjoy-loneliness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I enjoy loneliness.🍁" /><published>2019-03-05T02:42:54+08:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T02:42:54+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/05/I-enjoy-loneliness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/05/I-enjoy-loneliness.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is sometimes scary to see that how comfortable we grow with our loneliness. Sometimes using it as a blanket to shield ourselves from the cold of unknown minds, sometimes encountering a language so foreign in our dear ones that turn us inward into our own shells, sometimes in the resentments on the table that never reached a path of understanding and sometimes when you learn that maladjusted interiors of your shell is something that has bound you. You may or may not find complete peace there. But sometimes when the voices outside listen a little less, one learns to speak with themselves submerged in their own loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Praising it like a religion that you practice each day, this affect became a ritual when the teacher told you the importance of self expression, but you came across a duality each day. Whether it was your father who said “No” to those half questions that started with “May I..?”, whether it was your friends who thought that you seem comfortable with everything that they forgot to look at you, thereafter, whether it was your loved one who thought that when I say that, “I enjoy loneliness”, I was just hoping that he could fight for me this one time. But he laughed a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know there is a sense of comfort that each of us find in solitude. A solitude that some find in bookstores or in the corner of your L-shaped sofa and some others find it in their beds after a long day. But what if somebody gets too comfortable with solitude? 
It is scary to see how loneliness sometimes spreads like a plague all over your existence. And your body that becomes a host to it’s finest impressions of being strong, gets comfortable. It’s scary how it inhabits so deeply in your heart that you now don’t shine when people knock at the doors. It’s scary how it becomes our skin, and we get so comfortable with it each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know there is a balance in solitude. I hope that each one of you embrace that solitude.
I want you to be comfortable in your skin infront of others as much as you gain confidence in being comfortable with it yourself. I want you to be aware of a light that is found in each varied relationship, you just need patience for it to flourish, not perish.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">There is brave in each of you.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/04/There-is-brave-in-each-of-you.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="There is brave in each of you." /><published>2019-03-04T02:42:54+08:00</published><updated>2019-03-04T02:42:54+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/04/There-is-brave-in-each-of-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/04/There-is-brave-in-each-of-you.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have heard from the elders that life gets easy after you achieve milestones, some people might define these as intermingled with the successful careers, some might find peace in the loved ones that have been watching their back and some might still be finding the milestones. But there are times, when one is walking down that road. Sometimes wandering a little because that path doesn’t excite them anymore, sometimes exploring with caution as they are still unsure that what will the next destination bring and sometimes just a little scared. Because who ever said that growing up brings new experiences and difficulties, forgot to tell us the value of bravery. And most importantly, to accept that one is not brave enough each day but can surpass it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entangled amongst the little pavements that we find on each of the road that makes our path, we decorate it with the things that we aspire from life. Amidst that rigmarole, we forget that everyday is not about walking on that road with the brave face, sometimes as one is walking on the sidewalk just gathering courage to step on the road back. One is still brave. Ofcourse, we find bravery as a heroic demeanour that is endearing to the finest human potential. I might add a little to it’s stature, I think each one of you is brave. I think it’s brave when you get up in the morning and construct a road map that you will undertake today even if your soul is weary and your mind is shouting or completely numb from inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s brave when each one of you get up each day, watching the voyage called life and swimming through each hurdle with your effort. I think it’s brave, because each one of us reach a point of giving up and sometimes while there is a complete disequilibrium stopping us. We differ from our homeostasis, not because we don’t believe in one. But because, you’re trying to redefine the boundaries. And no matter where you are in life. If you get up each day whether this time you’re brave enough to walk on the road or the pavement calls you today. Or whether some day, you decide to contribute to the bravery of the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want you to know that after each scary storm, There is brave in each of you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I remember that it hurt.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/01/I-remember-that-it-hurt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I remember that it hurt." /><published>2019-03-01T02:42:54+08:00</published><updated>2019-03-01T02:42:54+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/01/I-remember-that-it-hurt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/01/I-remember-that-it-hurt.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know how certain things which while they break, shatter into a million pieces just as silently as one fine day it builds back. Despite located on the left side, why do we still believe it to be right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh heart, I remember you falling for a person who amidst the crowd felt like a home, speaking a language that you danced on it’s tunes, a boy who wore a grey sweatshirt sculpted greatly for a shelter and also arms that looked as though they were meant for me only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unknowingly I kept your heart safely with me, maybe, only because I wanted it to be shattered into a million pieces. The calm was coming to a slow end, and I was hoping that what I see is just a strong wind but it came as a storm. As you slowly started withdrawing day by day. I kept myself pre-occupied with the notion, that sometimes souls become so weary of each other. That sometimes despite having truckloads of faith and trust, I was ignoring the bells that lingered somewhere in the air that the end was approaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know how heartbreaks are considered heroic or a blissful trauma that one learns resilience from. But I found myself resistant to this thought. I should have known that despite narrating the stories of my ventricles. I was not yet closer to believe that sometimes people who are gazing are not here to stay. Everytime I stood there blurting “I love you”, only to hear the tunes of my disgraceful words just like how the mountain echoes back. Everytime I ran through your ribcage, only to be satisfied that the heart that was missing is placed deeply under my fissures. I was somewhere missing that while my fingers were stiching a life together with you. You made me believe that each of my thread came to be a little weak to tie you together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For what it’s worth, I collided with you one fine day. Only to see how the course would 
change the very next day. You know how beautiful this tale was till the time I was the author. But who knew co-writers existed all along. I fell and then I fell apart. Only this time, the tunes were an ode that I dedicated to you. My therapist called these tunes that have been guiding my other relationships. Maybe I’m wrong or maybe right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours, &lt;br /&gt;
Fair one!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Where can you find your soulmate?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/25/Where-can-you-find-your-soulmate.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where can you find your soulmate?" /><published>2019-02-25T02:42:54+08:00</published><updated>2019-02-25T02:42:54+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/25/Where-can-you-find-your-soulmate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/25/Where-can-you-find-your-soulmate.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hello&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Straddling my whole life in search of this one person that would be destined to be regarded as soulmate. The dictionary says that the person should “ideally suit” and most of the writers dearly entangle the testament of the word around the person who could make you the happiest and could complete you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this cogitation and being immensely preoccupied with the notion of finding one accidentally. Maybe somewhere down the road as it is shown in the movies, somewhere in the tuition classes that I looked forward as an event to meet new people from different schools, or that new boy in that section or maybe a friend that I now talk to a little more or maybe the boy that I’m currently crushing over or a person who will eventually join this journey! Because oh destiny! You really make us dream of a distant reality painted by a little imagination and almost expecting a little surprise out of it. A plan that we have in our heads, but obviously would want it’s course of action to be taken bit by bit along the secret route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immersed in these thoughts, my head today entered a different path. Maybe soulmate is not someone to be found in an extraordinary manner or someone with the ideal completeness. Maybe we all are surrounded by various soulmates, everyone as a different piece of various puzzles. But each piece, fitting somewhere in somebody’s puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know how while playing puzzles, piling up on my anxiety since childhood, fascinated with puzzles but always a little unhappy that how precisely I want each piece to fit in and the picture to sit on a proper plane. The proper plane might please my little obsessions. But I surely discovered a big answer, how the puzzle even when it is complete, the surface still has it ups and downs. Each piece still has it boundaries, certain boundaries sticking onto each other perfectly and certain just trying to fit in. Each piece trying to make it all a little complete. A complete that I now furnish with minute gaps, various pieces, ill-defined boundaries but a picture so brave that it leaves a sense of completeness. What if soulmate was not the person who was complete, but a person who makes you feel a little more of each thing, who conducts your heart to bang the loudest, a friend who tries to make you laugh a little lounder, a person who is time zones away but is still attentive, a person who is making an effort to mend a bond, a person who is dragging you out of the cellar of thoughts you locked yourself in, the person who gave you last slice or pizza or the last part of cornetto. And maybe you will not find all of it in one single person, and maybe, just maybe, soulmates were never meant that way. Maybe soulmates were the people that you keep discovering each day and leaving a little of your soul in each of them and they in return keep it alive. Maybe in the big picture, my dear. You’ve been surrounded with many. And maybe the whole picture seems little incomplete. But what’s the fascination about puzzles? If you don’t discover each piece in it’s own time and find a place for it to fit. Give it a look around or call the soulmate that you just remembered.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How do you know that you’re in love?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/23/how-do-you-know-that-youre-in-love.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How do you know that you’re in love?" /><published>2019-02-23T02:42:54+08:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T02:42:54+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/23/how-do-you-know-that-youre-in-love</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/23/how-do-you-know-that-youre-in-love.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love, was the letter L that came after you did a match with your crush through the game of FLAMES back in school. Maybe, the love would stay you thought, because both of your names would never change and the count of 7 would always prove that love was bound to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love, was the smile on your face when you looked at him. You knew it was different from your normal smile, because you had read somewhere that while in love you smile a little more deeply. It was the electric rush found by holding his hands. Yes, you indeed felt your cheeks go red. Hoping, that maybe. Just maybe, he was feeling the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love was catching a glimpse in the morning assemblies or while passing through the corridor. Love was saving the seat in the bus till the time somebody inquired about that seat. Because after all, he forwarded a text that read as “10 signs that you’re in love”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love, was that person who remembered each detail about you, it was the same person who was interested to listen to your plan A, B, C and even more not because he wanted to please it with a reply, but because he was shaping his plans accordingly, it was the 2:00 am conversations at night where everyone was asleep but you were awake as if discovering him was an adventure, love was the number of things that you wanted to tell him but you can’t because if you answer the question without him raising the question, he might think that he did the right thing by not asking you the question, love was when you wanted to hold onto him despite any circumstance, love was in his voice that made the same rigmarole of daily conversations, love was wishing for him, love was being comforted in each other’s silence, love now came with excitement only wrapped under a sense of comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love was when you looked at him and you never thought about how you wanted anything else. Because, in that moment you had everything you wanted. It was under the same person who managed to increase your heartbeat and also soften it bit by bit. 
And honestly, if you’ve found this, that is best way to know that you’re in love.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>